{
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "The Assam region was separated from the Bengal Presidency as \"North-East Frontier\" in the year",
        "options": [
          "A. 1874",
          "B. 1889",
          "C. 1861",
          "D. 1826"
        ],
        "answer": "A. 1874"
      },
      {
        "question": "The illustration work of the medieval Assamese text \"Hastividyarnava\" was done by",
        "options": [
          "A. Suryakhari Daibaigya",
          "B. Sukumar Borkaith",
          "C. Dibar and Ddosai",
          "D. Rama Saraswati"
        ],
        "answer": "B. Sukumar Borkaith"
      },
      {
        "question": "The Gohain Kamal Ali road was constructed during the reign of",
        "options": [
          "A. Nara Narayan",
          "B. Parikshit Narayan",
          "C. Viswa Singha",
          "D. Raghu Dev"
        ],
        "answer": "A. Nara Narayan"
      },
      {
        "question": "The first Ahom Monarch to assume the Hindu title \"Swarganarayan\" was",
        "options": [
          "A. Siva Singha",
          "B. Pratap Singha",
          "C. Jayadhwaj Singha",
          "D. Suhungmung"
        ],
        "answer": "D. Suhungmung"
      },
      {
        "question": "The first rebellion against the British rule in Assam in 1828 was led by",
        "options": [
          "A. Piyali Phukan",
          "B. Maniram Dewan",
          "C. Gomdhar Knowar",
          "D. Piyali Baruah"
        ],
        "answer": "C. Gomdhar Knowar"
      },
      {
        "question": "Who was the author of the book \"India against Itself\"",
        "options": [
          "A. Dr. Hiren Gohain",
          "B. Dr. Mamani Roysom Goswami",
          "C. Homen Borgohain",
          "D. Dr. Sanjib Barua"
        ],
        "answer": "D. Dr. Sanjib Barua"
      },
      {
        "question": "The Dhodar Ali is constructed during the reign of",
        "options": [
          "A. Rudra Singha",
          "B. Gadadhar Singha",
          "C. Pramatta Singha",
          "D. Siva Singha"
        ],
        "answer": "B. Gadadhar Singha"
      },
      {
        "question": "The Jaysagar Tank was excavated under the reign of which of the following Kings",
        "options": [
          "A. Rudra Singha",
          "B. Gadadhar Singha",
          "C. Siva Singha",
          "D. Rajeswar Singha"
        ],
        "answer": "A. Rudra Singha"
      },
      {
        "question": "The district which was separated from Assam and was given to East Pakistan in the year 1947 was",
        "options": [
          "A. Khulna",
          "B. Sylhet",
          "C. Chittagong",
          "D. Sholashahar"
        ],
        "answer": "B. Sylhet"
      },
      {
        "question": "In Assam, a source of hot water spring is situated in",
        "options": [
          "A. Nambor Reserve Forest",
          "B. Parashuram Kunda",
          "C. Orang Wildlife Sanctuary",
          "D. Manas Nationa Park"
        ],
        "answer": "A. Nambor Reserve Forest"
      },
      {
        "question": "Kamakhya Temple was rebuilt by which one of the following Koch King",
        "options": [
          "A. Biswa Singha",
          "B. Raghu Deva",
          "C. Naranarayan",
          "D. Prananarayan"
        ],
        "answer": "C. Naranarayan"
      },
      {
        "question": "Kanaklata Barua became a martyr of which one of the following national movements",
        "options": [
          "A. Non-Cooperation Movement",
          "B. Quit India Movement",
          "C. Civil Disobedience Movement",
          "D. Swadeshi Movement"
        ],
        "answer": "B. Quit India Movement"
      },
      {
        "question": "The Patkai Bum range makes the boundary between",
        "options": [
          "A. India and Bhutan",
          "B. India and China",
          "C. India and Bangladesh",
          "D. India and Burma"
        ],
        "answer": "D. India and Burma"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which one of the following places is the confluence of three highly revered pilgrimage for the Hindu, Muslim and Buddhists",
        "options": [
          "A. Parashuram Kunda",
          "B. Dekiakhowa Namghar",
          "C. Hajo",
          "D. Barpeta"
        ],
        "answer": "C. Hajo"
      },
      {
        "question": "Siang, joined by Lohit and Dibang makes which of the following rivers",
        "options": [
          "A. Jia Bharali",
          "B. Dikhow",
          "C. Subansiri",
          "D. Brahmaputra"
        ],
        "answer": "D. Brahmaputra"
      }
    ]
  }
  